

# About Me

Hi! I am Nedeljko Ružić, a dedicated software developer with more than 3.5 years of hands-on experience. My profound passion for programming drives me to continuously strive for self-improvement each day. Renowned for being a team player, I excel in effective communication. I am perpetually on the lookout for fresh challenges and eagerly embrace new knowledge to further enhance my skills.

# Bio

nenor1995@gmail.com

J Phone

+38766151304

Address

Istočno Sarajevo

# Professional Skills

## Languages

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- C#
- T-SQL

# Frameworks and Libraries

- React
- Angular 2+ AngularJS
- .NET 6
- · .NET (Core)
- ASP.NET MVC ASP.NET Web API
- Razor
- Entity
- LINQ
- Express.js
- Ionic Bootstrap
- Material UI
- Angular Material Design
- ΔPIs
- Web API 2, REST APIs, Stripe, WooCommerce API, Google Maps
- iText
- BuildFire SDK

### CI/CD Pipelines

- · Github Actions Azure DevOps
- Jenkins

## Databases

- MongoDB
- MS SQL Server
- SOLite
- Firebase

# **Tools and Enviroments**

- Visual Studio
- Visual Studio Code
- iTextPDF
- Git GitHub
- Figma
- Babel
- Node JS
- Webpack, Gulp, NPM, Yarn
- Azure
- Jasmine

### Paradigms

- Agile Software Development (Scrum)
- Microservices
- Serverless
- Model View Controller (MVC)
- Refactoring
- Unit Testing

# Work Experience



## Software Engineer at BuildFire

January, 2020 - July, 2023

- Developed Mobile Apps based on Apache Cordova (Vanilla JS, ReactJS, AngularJS, NodeJS, Firebase, MongoDB).
- Writing technical specifications, project requirements and providing project documentations.
- Developed resuable components for future use within the BuildFire SDK such as Control List View, Widget List View, Content Slider. Swipeable Drawer. These components have intention of making the UI more standardized and lowering time cost at developing such features.
- Developed dozens of features/plugins that are being daily used by more than 1.000.000 users

- Bugs fixing and support for production apps
- Helping other team members with guidance, pair programming and knowledge transfers
- · Participated in peer code reviews
- · Interviewed the candidates
- · Defining and executing onboarding process

## Full Stack Engineer at https://dass.ba/

March, 2022 - August, 2022

- Developed survey system that allows users to earn money by completing surveys.
- Contains CRM for managing users, demographic data, surveys and payments
- · Contains four different roles: Admin, Collaborator, Survey Buyer, Examinee
- Infobip integration for messaging system (sms/email)
- · Zoho mailing service
- Mobile Friendly

#### Stack:

- Angular 13 Frontend
- .NET 6 Backend
- SOL Database
- Azure

## Full Stack Engineer at Vatrosistemi d.o.o

May, 2021 - February, 2022

Developed web and mobile application for managing the whole company.

Web application allows administration to keep track of:

- Work being done inside the company, upcoming schedules etc.
- Monitoring workers and their success
- Any activity in the system

Mobile application allows service workers to get their daily work done. Some of the features app includes:

- · Barcode scanning using Zebra devices
- Geo location tracking (admin can track workers on the map)
- · Offline mode

#### Stack:

- Angular 11 Frontend
- . NET 6 Backend
- SQL Database
- Ionic + Angular Mobile Application

## Full Stack Engineer at http://agrosym.ues.rs.ba/

Jan, 2020 - March, 2020

Developed a website for one of the biggest agriculture symposiums in Europe.

Some of the features website includes:

- Language translations English/Serbian
- Online registration for attending the symposium
- Mailing system

### Stack:

- Angular Frontend
- Node JS Backend
- MongoDB Database

## O Full Stack Engineer at https://bhembassy.jp/

June, 2019 - August, 2019

Developed a website for Bosnia and Herzegovina embassy in Japan.

Some of the features website includes:

- Language translations English/Serbian/Japan
- Interface for creating posts with images that show up on the home page

### Stack

- Angular Frontend
- Node JS Backend
- MongoDB Database

### O Internship at Prointer

October, 2019 - December, 2019

While participating in educational IT project from country I was selected to join internship in the Prointer company. I had a senior developer which was my mentor for the time being there. Developed C# application for CRUD operations in SQL database. Developed full stack intern application for the company which utilizes Angular, C# and SQL. I was offered a job there but better oportunity came up.

## Education

 Java - development of client-server distributed applications and web services ICBL, Banja Luka (Bosnia and Herzegovina)

2019 - 2019

Participated in country project of educating people to get into IT. Went to Java course where I have learned basic concepts of of it and developed few small applications during scholarship. Been selected as best out of 100 people that were attending on the project. Helped in various classes (Angular, PHP, C#, QA) to people that needed guidance or any kind of help.

# O C# Programming Basics Course

2018 - 201

Learned basics of using C# in development